<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Neilrenicker.com</title>
    <description>The design, development, and workflow blog of Neil Renicker</description>
    <link>http://neilrenicker.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://neilrenicker.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Terminal Shortcuts</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m trying to get faster at using my terminal. I plan for this to become a growing list of shortcuts I want to commonly use for speedier terminal navigation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realize there are &lt;a href=&#39;http://www.gnu.org/software/bash/manual/bashref.html&#39;&gt;references&lt;/a&gt; for this sort of thing already—but this isn&amp;#8217;t meant to be comprehensive. It&amp;#8217;s meant to be a simplified and helpful layman&amp;#8217;s guide. This is mainly for my own benefit, but as always, you&amp;#8217;re welcome to follow along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#39;clearing_and_navigation&#39;&gt;Clearing and navigation:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delete line up to beginning: &lt;code&gt;Ctrl + U&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Delete complete line: &lt;code&gt;Ctrl + A, Ctrl + K&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Cancel current command: &lt;code&gt;Ctrl + C&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Recall last deleted command: &lt;code&gt;Ctrl + Y&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Go to beginning of line: &lt;code&gt;Ctrl + A&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Go to end of line: &lt;code&gt;Ctrl + E&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Remove words ahead: &lt;code&gt;Ctrl + K&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Remove characters to left, until beginning of word: &lt;code&gt;Ctrl + W&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://neilrenicker.com/notes/terminal-shortcuts</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://neilrenicker.com/notes/terminal-shortcuts</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Feedback Loop</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently took two vacation days to stay at home, be with my family, and work on side projects. I was prepared to be inspired and diligent. I had a simple, yet ambitious plan for creating things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, it didn’t work. I did very little writing (ironically, I started writing this article before work on the Monday &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; my mini vacation). I got a little done, but for the most part, I was sidetracked and a bit bored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bored! How could I be bored when there are a thousand wonderful things in our industry to be learning and creating? I contrast this with the “filled-to-the-brim”, “always-on” inspiration I feel during the work week when I’m working on other things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve said this before, and it’s still as true as ever: &lt;em&gt;We’re most inspired when we should be working on something else.&lt;/em&gt; What’s going on here? What’s the magic that’s present during regular working hours, but vaporizes during vacation or dedicated “side project” time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Passive thought?&lt;/strong&gt; Do our brains have a &lt;a href=&#39;http://www.arlovance.com/content/articles/activepassive.pdf&#39;&gt;peripheral thought life&lt;/a&gt; that flourishes when not given direct attention?&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time gluttony?&lt;/strong&gt; Do we thrive under the constraints and pressure of small time slots, but get fat and lazy when we have a large block of time to do whatever we want?&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bad working habits?&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re like me, you’re constantly optimizing your work habits to get the most out of the time you have. But I wonder if the prospect of 2-3 full days of working only on stuff we love is just too good to be true. Have snappy online social services ruined our ability to focus and &lt;a href=&#39;http://calnewport.com/blog/2012/11/21/knowledge-workers-are-bad-at-working-and-heres-what-to-do-about-it/&#39;&gt;press through difficult work&lt;/a&gt;? Have we succumbed to the tyranny of the push notification, and surrendered up our mental disciplines in return?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#39;your_job_is_not_a_curse&#39;&gt;Your Job is Not a Curse&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of those hypotheses for inspiration slump lead me to conclude that if you’re serious about side projects, your day job isn’t a curse. It might be your biggest blessing! The time that you have to write, work on side projects, and self-teach may be short, but it can have a higher net value than day upon day of free time. You appreciate your free time when you get it, and you’re constrained to work quickly and with focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a remarkable feedback loop present between day work and night work. Even if your day job is completely unrelated to your hobbies, you hear things at work that give you ideas to boost up your side projects. You have the benefit of the energy, camaraderie, and the criticism of your coworkers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then at home, you practice things in your side projects that make your more competent at work. You’re refreshed by working on stuff you really want to, and you develop insight and skills that make you a more valuable employee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Killing either part of this balanced feedback loop can break the circuit and stop the flow.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://neilrenicker.com/articles/feedback-loop</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://neilrenicker.com/articles/feedback-loop</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Describe Design with GIFs and Annotations</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In a distributed workplace, and in online communication with clients, talking about design is difficult. Talking about animation and interaction in design is even more difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve found that the best way to describe movement in interfaces is with &lt;em&gt;animated GIFs&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;annotated images&lt;/em&gt;. I&amp;#8217;ll walk you quickly through how I make it happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#39;gifs_for_a_good_cause&#39;&gt;GIFs for a good cause&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GIFs are good for more than showing &lt;a href=&#39;http://neilrenicker.com/img/posts/2013-10-23-bear-trash.gif&#39;&gt;dumpster-diving bears&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#39;http://neilrenicker.com/img/posts/2013-10-23-cute-puppy.gif&#39;&gt;cute puppies&lt;/a&gt;. Put them to work in lots of cool ways by recording stuff on your screen:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mock up faux Javascript animations by adding / removing class names in CSS, or switching Photoshop layers on and off &lt;img alt=&#39;Mock up Javascript interactions with GIFs&#39; src=&#39;../img/posts/2013-10-23-animating-javascript-with-gifs.gif&#39; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Easily show visual bugs in interface interactions&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Record quick how-to&amp;#8217;s showing the process of performing a complicated programming or technical task &lt;img alt=&#39;Teach technical tasks with GIFs&#39; src=&#39;../img/posts/2013-10-23-animating-tasks-with-gifs.gif&#39; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How I do it:&lt;/strong&gt; I use &lt;a href=&#39;http://www.cockos.com/licecap/&#39;&gt;LICEcap&lt;/a&gt; for recording GIFs on my screen. It&amp;#8217;s free, it&amp;#8217;s simple to use, and it has a feature set that&amp;#8217;s just right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;ll never have to open Photoshop or a video-editing app. LICEcap simply outputs an animated GIF of a selected area of your screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#39;ugly_annotations&#39;&gt;Ugly Annotations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pictures and screenshots are valuable, but they become even more helpful when you write on them. Annotations need not be pretty. They just need to be easy to spot, and quick to digest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Point out exactly where a visual bug is happening on an interface &lt;img alt=&#39;Describe bugs with annotated images&#39; src=&#39;../img/posts/2013-10-23-annotating-bugs-with-skitch.jpg&#39; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Use circles and arrows to draw attention to stuff&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Quickly teach a technical task by scribbling steps on a screenshot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How I do it:&lt;/strong&gt; I use &lt;a href=&#39;http://evernote.com/skitch/&#39;&gt;Skitch for Mac&lt;/a&gt; to make annotations. Skitch even has a hotkey (&lt;code&gt;⌘ + Shift + 5&lt;/code&gt;) to take a screen grab and immediately open it in the app. Speed is the key here for me. Skitch is super fast, and has just a few simple features for adding bright, bold annotations to images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, you can use &lt;code&gt;⌘ + Shift + 4&lt;/code&gt; (default in OS X) to take a screen grab and open it in the graphics program of your choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I annotate with Skitch, I upload the image to &lt;a href=&#39;http://getcloudapp.com/&#39;&gt;Cloud App&lt;/a&gt; and share the link, or drag the image into a Github issue to display it inline. If Cloud App doesn&amp;#8217;t suite you, &lt;a href=&#39;https://droplr.com/hello&#39;&gt;Droplr&lt;/a&gt; is a worthy alternative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#39;use_this_stuff_in_github_issues_and_forum_answers_please&#39;&gt;Use this stuff in Github issues and forum answers, please&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using these two simple communication tools will make your Github issues and forum answers like 500% better. Use them for that. The internet will thank you and you&amp;#8217;ll be my hero. Also, there&amp;#8217;s no reason you can&amp;#8217;t communicate this way in email, chat, and blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://neilrenicker.com/notes/describe-design-with-gifs-and-annotations</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://neilrenicker.com/notes/describe-design-with-gifs-and-annotations</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Alfred + Harvest</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&#39;http://www.getharvest.com/&#39;&gt;Harvest&lt;/a&gt; every day for tracking time to projects. Harvest makes time tracking as painless as it can be, I suppose. The web app UI is uncluttered and sane. The feature set is just right. The &lt;a href=&#39;http://www.getharvest.com/mac&#39;&gt;Mac app&lt;/a&gt; is suitable. And &lt;a href=&#39;https://github.com/harvesthq/api&#39;&gt;the API&lt;/a&gt; is clean and well-documented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What more could a worker ask for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, not much… except an Alfred workflow to control the timer. You &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; using &lt;a href=&#39;http://www.alfredapp.com/&#39;&gt;Alfred&lt;/a&gt;, aren&amp;#8217;t you? It&amp;#8217;s a simple yet insanely powerful little Mac app for launching applications, opening files, and best of all, running custom scripts (or &amp;#8220;workflows&amp;#8221;) to speed up repetitive tasks. It&amp;#8217;s the first application I install when I get a new Mac, and it&amp;#8217;s the one you probably shouldn&amp;#8217;t wait another moment to &lt;a href=&#39;http://www.alfredapp.com/#download&#39;&gt;go download&lt;/a&gt; if you don&amp;#8217;t have it already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;#8217;ve downloaded Alfred and purchased the &lt;a href=&#39;http://www.alfredapp.com/powerpack/&#39;&gt;Powerpack&lt;/a&gt; (just get it—you&amp;#8217;ll thank me later), you&amp;#8217;ll be all ready to speed up your Harvest time tracking. I wrote a simple workflow for Alfred to manage Harvest timers. I fondly call it &lt;strong&gt;alfred-harvest&lt;/strong&gt;, and it&amp;#8217;s here for you to kick the tires and drive around the block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s what &lt;strong&gt;alfred-harvest&lt;/strong&gt; can do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;view today&amp;#8217;s timers&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;start / stop a timer&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;view and add notes&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;launch your Harvest web app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the impatient, &lt;a href=&#39;https://github.com/neilrenicker/alfred-harvest/releases&#39;&gt;view releases and download from Github&lt;/a&gt;. For the rest of you, animated gifs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Starting a new timer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;alfred-harvest new timer&#39; src=&#39;http://f.cl.ly/items/0R2w093T4505281R272V/harvest-new.gif&#39; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Toggling today&amp;#8217;s timers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;alfred-harvest toggle timer&#39; src=&#39;http://f.cl.ly/items/0V3d0B0T0H310q1C0X2S/harvest-toggle.gif&#39; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adding a note:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;alfred-harvest add note&#39; src=&#39;http://f.cl.ly/items/0P3B0b03102X2M2t153f/harvest-note.gif&#39; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s the way you do it. I hope you enjoy the workflow as much as I do! &lt;a href=&#39;https://github.com/neilrenicker/alfred-harvest/&#39;&gt;Check out the project on Github&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#39;https://github.com/neilrenicker/alfred-harvest/releases&#39;&gt;head directly to the downloads page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://neilrenicker.com/articles/alfred-harvest</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://neilrenicker.com/articles/alfred-harvest</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fix: Finder Columns Too Wide</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently had a little OS X Finder meltdown. I somehow had set my Finder columns to a very large width permanently; I could temporarily drag to resize the column width, but every time I opened a new Finder window, the columns would reset to be extremely wide again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;Screenshot: wide Finder columns&#39; src=&#39;../img/posts/2013-09-29-finder-columns-too-wide.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I lived with the annoyance for a long time because I couldn&amp;#8217;t find any preferences to set the default finder width. I finally discovered the (hidden) solution:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hold the &lt;code&gt;option/alt&lt;/code&gt; key&lt;/strong&gt; while dragging to resize a Finder column width. Finder will remember that width for future windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and if you&amp;#8217;re wondering how I have those cool tabs in my Finder, look no further than the excellent &lt;a href=&#39;http://www.trankynam.com/xtrafinder/&#39;&gt;XtraFinder&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s solid, and has lots of great keyboard shortcuts for powerusers—I can&amp;#8217;t imagine ever going back to OS X default finder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&#39;http://forums.macrumors.com/showpost.php?p=3499315&amp;amp;postcount=5&#39;&gt;a MacRumors user&lt;/a&gt; for the tip.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://neilrenicker.com/notes/finder-columns-too-wide</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://neilrenicker.com/notes/finder-columns-too-wide</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Green Lights</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you work on a team, or if you’re trying to break into a populous career as freelancer, you probably know what it&amp;#8217;s like to feel as if your destiny is the hands of a group of powerful gatekeepers. Your boss, your peers, conference organizers, book publishers, even the disinterested public – they all seem to be lining up with stiff shoulders to keep you from breaking in and getting the opportunities you long for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The longer you live, the more you’re going to bump into people who don&amp;#8217;t validate, don’t encourage, or don’t even acknowledge you. It’s not because your friends are cruel and heartless. It’s just that they don’t have any reason to be impressed with you yet; or maybe, they simply have different goals and interests than yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what I’ve been reminding myself of as often as I can:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These folks don&amp;#8217;t have the final say on who I am and what I can do, and—&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;If I&amp;#8217;m waiting for validation to do something meaningful, I&amp;#8217;m probably never going to get it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Waiting for a green light to do something I know I can do is foolish and fruitless. If the job hasn’t been done, then even the “qualified” people haven’t done it. I guess that makes me qualified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have crazy ideas! I have big dreams! But no one cares about mere ideas. Ideas are paper thin. If I don’t act on them, they are meaningless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m done waiting to get backed, funded, and qualified. The green light is a myth. No, I might not be the best guy for the job; but as long as there’s a job to do, the best guy to do it is the guy who gets it done.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://neilrenicker.com/articles/green-lights</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://neilrenicker.com/articles/green-lights</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Changes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A little over six months ago, I spent my working hours mostly in solitude. I was a freelancer, living the freelancer&amp;#8217;s dream. I ran a small design shop; I had wonderful clients, fast internet, a pot of coffee always on, and the novelty of a self-managed schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve turned a corner, though. After six months of training at my &lt;a href=&#39;http://seesparkbox.com/apprenticeships&#39;&gt;Sparkbox apprenticeship&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;#8217;m excited to say that I&amp;#8217;ve accepted a position as a front-end developer there. I won&amp;#8217;t be working from home as much, I won&amp;#8217;t be managing clients, and I won&amp;#8217;t be the master of my own schedule. There are a few things I &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; be doing, though, as a result of this welcome change:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll be enjoying the company of my new friends every day.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;#8217;m a certain introvert - I &lt;a href=&#39;http://the-pastry-box-project.net/chris-coyier/2013-april-3/&#39;&gt;recharge on alone time&lt;/a&gt;, and big groups of people stress me out. But the camaraderie of a few kind friends does wonders for morale - and I&amp;#8217;ve become convinced that I do better work now that I&amp;#8217;m surrounded by people whose skill and passion surpasses my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll be a part of something bigger than myself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; As a solo act, I developed a thick skin, and a strong spirit of self-sufficiency. These are valuable traits to be sure! Managing clients and handling projects alone carved out a rugged can-do, self-starter mentality in me that I still enjoy the benefits of. But there&amp;#8217;s a whole side of life that I was unwittingly missing out on - the joy of working on a &lt;em&gt;team&lt;/em&gt;, where the praise and criticism and responsibility of the group are all evenly distributed. There&amp;#8217;s a sense of jolly brotherhood in this arrangement that puts a song on my lips and feather in my step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll be able to learn and teach to a degree that I hadn&amp;#8217;t experienced before.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; In some ways, I felt that during my apprenticeship, I learned more in that six months than I ever could have in six years of tackling the same problems alone. Conversely, I&amp;#8217;ve been given opportunities to teach and &lt;em&gt;share&lt;/em&gt; the things I&amp;#8217;ve learned in ways I&amp;#8217;d only dreamed about before. I certainly don&amp;#8217;t think you have to be in a team environment to grow and share, but occasional accountability and encouragement are a great fit for my personality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll be able to narrow my focus to doing mainly what I&amp;#8217;m good at.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;#8217;m not a great businessman. I did decently at managing my business because I was the only one to do it. My first love is the work itself, though. Being an employee means I can focus in with precision and passion on what I do best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Sparkbox is the &lt;a href=&#39;http://seesparkbox.com/foundry/meet_neil&#39;&gt;next leg of my journey&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#8217;m excited about what I can give, and what I can take. The changes are stark, but the change is worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;You don&#39;t need more time, you just need to decide&quot;
  &lt;span class=&#39;quote-source&#39;&gt;-Seth Godin&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://neilrenicker.com/articles/changes</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://neilrenicker.com/articles/changes</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Designers with Biceps</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are the links to resources I mentioned during my talk:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://neil.re/peoples&#39;&gt;neil.re/peoples&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;A list of must-follow thought leaders, resources, and blogs focused on front-end web development&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://neil.re/side-projects&#39;&gt;neil.re/side-projects&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Resources for thinking of web side projects&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the quotes I mentioned during the talk, with links to each of the articles / books referenced:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;A designer who does not write markup and css is not designing for the web, but drawing pictures.&amp;#8221; &lt;br /&gt;-Andy Rutledge, &lt;a href=&#39;http://andyrutledge.com/web-design-is-product-design.php&#39;&gt;Web Design is Product Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Happiest when exploring the intersection between design and development, I can now take a website from visual concept right through to production-ready code. I can move between graphics application and browser at will, making changes late into production. The whole process feels like a two-way conversation between designer and developer, fluid and fleeting, yet set entirely within my own mind.&amp;#8221; &lt;br /&gt;-Paul Robert Lloyd, &lt;a href=&#39;http://the-pastry-box-project.net/clearleft/2013-june-6/&#39;&gt;Works Well With Others&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Challenge yourself. Humble yourself. Get over yourself. Whatever you do, make sure it’s well outside your comfort zone. You’ll learn and grow and become better, stronger, and a lot more self-assured. Learning to not care what others think about you – in a healthy way – is incredibly empowering.” &lt;br /&gt;-Jeff Haden, &lt;a href=&#39;http://www.inc.com/jeff-haden/your-most-important-business-investment.html&#39;&gt;Your Most Important Business Invesment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Being a great designer and a great developer is not an impossibility. With enough time and effort, you can become a designer or developer or both, no forehead horn required.” &lt;br /&gt;-Diogenes Brito, &lt;a href=&#39;https://diogenes.squarespace.com/blog/on-being-a-designer-and-a-developer-not-quite-unicorn-rare&#39;&gt;On Being A Designer And A Developer: Not Quite Unicorn Rare&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The horizontal stroke of the ‘T’ is the disposition for collaboration across disciplines. The vertical stroke of the ‘T’ is a depth of skill that allows them to contribute to the creative process.” &lt;br /&gt;-Tim Brown, &lt;a href=&#39;http://chiefexecutive.net/ideo-ceo-tim-brown-t-shaped-stars-the-backbone-of-ideoae%E2%84%A2s-collaborative-culture&#39;&gt;T-Shaped Stars: The Backbone of IDEO’s Collaborative Culture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Dude, suckin&amp;#8217; at something is the first step to being sorta good at something” &lt;br /&gt;-&lt;a href=&#39;http://konigi.com/notebook/wisdom-dog&#39;&gt;Jake the Dog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Pretending you know what you&amp;#8217;re doing is almost the same as knowing what you are doing, so just accept that you know what you&amp;#8217;re doing even if you don&amp;#8217;t and do it.&amp;#8221; &lt;br /&gt;-Bre Pettis and Kio Stark, &lt;a href=&#39;http://www.brepettis.com/blog/2009/3/3/the-cult-of-done-manifesto.html&#39;&gt;The Cult of Done Manifesto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://neilrenicker.com/speaking/designers-with-biceps</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://neilrenicker.com/speaking/designers-with-biceps</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fear and Code</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As I’m working through my &lt;a href=&#39;http://seesparkbox.com/apprenticeships&#39;&gt;apprenticeship at Sparkbox&lt;/a&gt;, there are a few ideas that have kept me going when I hit the paralyzing fear of a challenging programming problem:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#39;quote-right&#39;&gt;“Small strokes fell great oaks.”
  &lt;span class=&#39;quote-source&#39;&gt;–Benjamin Franklin&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only way to get somewhere is to start walking. If I feel really, really stuck, I open my Field Notes, grab a pen, and start sketching / writing out what my problem is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing things in English, like a story, is a good way to start a programming challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, the only problem is that my computer can’t read English. I start with the “once upon a time” – the one little piece of code I need to write so my computer knows the story is about to start. In Ruby, that might look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;code&gt;class Tree&lt;br /&gt;
  end&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There! Now I have “once upon a time”. I celebrate the small victories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the next thing I need to write? I figure that out, and write it. If it’s too hard or I don’t know what to write, I take what I thought I needed to write and cut it in half.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#39;always_try_to_be_doing_something&#39;&gt;Always try to be doing something&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try to always be doing something. Sometimes I might just be thinking – that’s OK, but it’s better to think by sketching or writing ideas down on a blank page / text document. If I catch myself staring off into space for a minute or so, I’m not making any progress with my code. If I have even an inkling of an idea for the next thing to write, I can just write it! I don’t have to wait until the code is perfectly formed in my head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#39;quote-right&#39;&gt;“Putting it on paper lets you start fixing it. If it stays in your head, a perfect idea, you’ll never share it with anyone.”
  &lt;span class=&#39;quote-source&#39;&gt;-Pixar, &lt;a href=&#39;http://www.pixartouchbook.com/blog/2011/5/15/pixar-story-rules-one-version.html&#39; title=&#39;Pixar story rules&#39;&gt;Pixar story rules&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s easier for a potter to work with a problem in his clay than it is to work with the problem in his head. If he touches one side of the pot, it responds, and he immediately knows the next thing to do. Even if he made the wrong touch, he knows that it was a bad touch. If all of his molding happens as planning in his head, he’s merely guessing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://neilrenicker.com/articles/fear-and-code</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://neilrenicker.com/articles/fear-and-code</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>On the Go</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For many years, I&amp;#8217;ve done the bulk of my design and development work on a big 27&amp;#8221; iMac. I always loved that huge screen and the simplicity of the iMac&amp;#8217;s design (only 1 cable, no tower, no fuss).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this time, I had a laptop as well, so I went to great pains to sync all of my stuff across the two devices with a combination of Dropbox, and iCloud, and Gmail. This worked OK, but I&amp;#8217;ve trimmed down my setup even further - and I don&amp;#8217;t think I&amp;#8217;ll ever go back!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sold my big iMac on eBay for a good price, and purchased components of my new setup for only a fraction of that selling price. Here&amp;#8217;s the overview:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;13&amp;#8221; Macbook Air&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;20&amp;#8221; Flat-Panel Cinema Display&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a href=&#39;http://www.amazon.com/Cooler-Master-Clutch-Ultrabook-R9-NBS-CLHS-GP/dp/B00A4BL6FS&#39;&gt;Cooler Master Clutch&lt;/a&gt; vertical Macbook stand&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Apple&amp;#8217;s wireless Magic Trackpad and wireless keyboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Air, in my opinion, is the perfect device for every situation. It&amp;#8217;s incredibly portable - light and thin. The 13&amp;#8221; size isn&amp;#8217;t too small if I don&amp;#8217;t have an external screen around, and I can close it up at work and at home where I do have a screen. It doesn&amp;#8217;t have impressive specs - just a 1.7 GHz processor and 4 GB of memory - but it performs blazingly fast for everything I do (web development and programming, using the Adobe Creative Suite, and foolishly keeping dozens of apps open at once).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part of my single device setup is that I don&amp;#8217;t have to bother with syncing issues anymore. If I&amp;#8217;m in the middle of a project at the end of a day, I can just snap the lid shut and pick back up right where I left off at my next stop!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I added details and links to the equipment &lt;a href=&#39;http://www.flickr.com/photos/neilrenicker/8562850179/&#39;&gt;on Flickr&lt;/a&gt; if you&amp;#8217;re interested.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://neilrenicker.com/articles/on-the-go</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://neilrenicker.com/articles/on-the-go</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>